DALE LARSEN

Senior Software Manager

Contact

Address

Ogden, UT, 84404

Phone

(801) 644-9624

E-mail

dale@dalelarsen.com

WWW

https://dalelarsen.com

Skills

Team Management

Project Management

Remote Work

Javascript

Angular

ReactJS

CSS/SCSS/SASS

SQL and NoSQL Databases

AWS

For all see "Technologies"

Senior Software Manager

I lead, architect, manage, and build web applications and business technical solutions, and see them through to completion.

Self-taught by running a web development company for over 12 years.

I have learned and developed skills in project/team management as well as many programming languages, frameworks, and libraries.

I am self-motivated and have proven that I can deliver short and long term needs. I currently work in a co-working space where I have been thriving for years. I can manage remote and in-house developers. I work very well in a remote environment.

For more info and a showcase of projects please go to https://dalelarsen.com

Work History

2015-09 -Current

Senior Software Development Manager

Fabuso, Ogden, UT

- Led and ran all the development and technology business needs of the company.
- Oversaw the acquisition of new clients and managed our development team, developing much of the software myself.
- Each new client involved building new custom software solutions, integrating 3rd party software, and migrating old systems to the corresponding replacements.
- Continued to fulfill previous duties of Senior Web Developer.

2007-11 -2015-09

Senior Full Stack Developer

Fabuso, Ogden, UT

- Architected web applications, reviewing each project and choosing frameworks and solutions that best fit each one.
- Managed development projects.
- Built and maintained software according to client needs.

2002-09 -2005-11

Website Manager

Achieve Auto Sales, Ogden, UT

Maintained company website for car dealership.

Kept up to date daily inventory on website and launched and managed eBay® listings for the cars.

Technologies

Angular 2+ (3 years)

Javascript (10+ years)

React (2 years)

Jquery (10+ years)

Nodejs (4 years)

Angularis (6 years)

Java (9 years)

AWS (8 years)

CSS (10+ years)

Firebase (4 years)

MySQL (10+ years)

Web Development (10+ years)

PHP

VueJS (2 years)

ChartJS

Mocha

Gatsby

TypeScript (4 years)

Photoshop (10+ years)

Adobe XD (2 years)

Git (5 years)

Bootstrap (6 years)

APIs

User Interface (UI)

JSON

XML

GitHub

MVC

NoSQL

AJAX

SVN (10+ years)

Scrum

HTML5 (10+ years)

Projects

For a showcase of projects please go to https://dalelarsen.com

Education

2002-08 -2005-05 High school: Computer Science

Roy High School - Roy, UT

References

- Kurt Othmer President/CEO at EEGInfo, Inc: (818) 970-5878
- Shaye Larsen CEO/Owner at West Bridge Auto Sales, Partner at Fabuso: (801) 388-4721
- Jared Hancock Business Coach/Consultant: (801) 389-8593
- Nick Drishinski Software Developer at Rockford Fosgate: (435) 757-9991
- Michael Wilson Director, Medicare Sales at eHealth, Inc: (801) 564-0879